# **Edward F. Martin, III**

## IT Systems Professional / Lead Quality Assurance Engineer

Cherry Hill, NJ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/b74f3abcd1ecbba3

Analytical, highly technical professional with extensive experience planning and executing all phases of software development lifecycle in line with aggressive project requirements. Engaging leader of multidisciplinary teams in achieving on-time project deliverables. Trusted business partner to gather and align requirements with project processes, ensuring continuous updates and full transparency through all project phases.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Principal Quality Assurance Engineer**

CA TECHNOLOGIES - Ewing, NJ - March 2008 to January 2015

Direct quality assurance processes for all software development projects, ensuring optimal performance, reliability, functionality and quality of products. Execute all testing, refinement and configuration prior to release.

#### **Principal Quality Assurance Engineer**

CA TECHNOLOGIES - Ewing, NJ - 2014 to 2015

- = 2014 2015 UIM for System z Unified Infrastructure Manager (a scalable monitoring solution)
- o Installed MYSQL database onto Windows 8 server
- o Added required SQL statements to database
- o Installed UIM hub component onto Windows 8 server
- o Provisioned zLinux VM and installed and configured UIM probe for z/VM on to zLinux VM
- o Designed test cases and bash scripts to generate system activity to ensure that the probe collected the system data and returned metrics to UIM hub; displayed them correctly in the UI
- o Tested that the critical alarms triggered when alarm thresholds exceeded the defined limits

# **Principal Quality Assurance Engineer**

CA TECHNOLOGIES - Ewing, NJ - 2013 to 2014

- = 2013 2014 CA Guest Manager for System z Project
- o Performed installation tests and regression testing in line with SDLC and SQA methodologies
- o Created a fix creation procedure for each system to deliver code fix to the customer. The fix creation procedures were in place before product went Beta.
- o Requested access to ftp server to place product deliverables and test download of deliverables. Placed Beta version of product deliverable on ftp server for customer download.
- o Worked with Product Owner, Scrum Master and Product Management to meet biweekly deadlines. Continually met long term goals of Product Development

#### **Principal Quality Assurance Engineer**

CA TECHNOLOGIES - Ewing, NJ - 2011 to 2013

- = 2011 -2013 CA AppLogic for System z Project
- o Directed weekly QA meetings between 5 CA associates in 3 countries: US, India, Czech Republic
- o Led Daily Agile Scrum meetings when Scrum Master was unavailable
- o Worked with Product Owner, Scrum Master and Product Management to meet Monthly deadlines

## **Principal Quality Assurance Engineer**

CA TECHNOLOGIES - Ewing, NJ - 2010 to 2011

- = 2010 2011 Software Configuration Service (SCS) phase of CA CSM
- o Analyzed and designed which product configuration options were appropriate for SCS
- o Trained three additional software engineers to assist with the SCS project for Enterprise Report Management (ERM) products
- o Transitioned and trained development team members with the new product build procedures that included creation of installation images (cart and pax files) and maintenance of CSM XML

#### **Principal Quality Assurance Engineer**

CA TECHNOLOGIES - Ewing, NJ - 2009 to 2010

- = 2009 2010 Software Deployment Service (SDS) phase of CA CSM and Product Packaging and source code repository transition
- o Coded, tested, debugged and fixed all defects for the Software Deployment Service phase turning over the code to Quality Assurance
- o Built SMP/E product carts and pax files manually from the source code repository (CA Endevor)
- o Converted the CA Bundl release 6.0 product installation to industry SMP/E standards; Also packaged the SIS and SDS XML with this release

#### Senior Quality Assurance Engineer

CA TECHNOLOGIES - Ewing, NJ - 2008 to 2009

- = 2008 2009 Software Installation Service (SIS) phase of CA CSM and Electronic Software Delivery (ESD)
- o Coded, tested, debugged and fixed all defects for the Software Installation Service phase turning over the code to Quality Assurance
- o Converted the Enterprise Report Management product line installation tapes into an electronic software delivery media (pax file)

EARLY CAREER
CA TECHNOLOGIES, Ewing, NJ
Senior Quality Assurance Engineer
Quality Assurance Engineer
Quality Assurance Technician

CIGNA SYSTEMS, Voorhees, NJ Network Control Technician Peripheral Equipment Operator

**EDUCATION** 

#### **BA in Liberal Arts**

Temple University - Philadelphia, PA

## **Diploma in Computer Programming**

Maxwell Institute - Norristown, PA

LINKS

http://www.linkedin.com/in/edwardfmartiniii

#### CERTIFICATIONS

#### **CSM - Certified Scrum Master**

February 2015 to February 2017 Certified Scrum Master, Scrum Alliance, License 00396343, February 2015 – February 2017

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Methodologies: SDLC, Agile Life Cycle Management, Waterfall Software Development

Administrative: Documentation Management, Vendor Relations, Stakeholder Engagement, Quality Assurance, Team Leadership, Training & Development, KPI and Reporting

Platforms: Windows, Linux, and UNIX platforms, Mainframe z/OS, z/VM with z/Linux and CMS

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: IBM Assembler, CLIST/REXX, SQL, Visual Basic, VBScript, HTML, XML, BASH and C

Tools: CA Clarity PPM, VersionOne (Agile), SharePoint, MS Office Suite/Products: Word, Excel, PowerPoint, HP ALM/QC, Rapid Test, CA Verify, CA Traps, SVN and Bugzilla

Mainframe Software: SMS, CICS, JES2, TSO, ISPF/PDF, VTAM, SMF, SMP/E, SLES, DFDSS, TCP/IP and others

CA Products: CA Common Services, CA Top Secret, CA Dispatch, CA Spool, CA View, CA Deliver, CA Output Management Web Viewer, CA DRAS, CA Endevor, CA VM:Secure, CA VM:Director, CA AppLogic for System z, CA Guest Manager for System z and CA UIM for System z

#### z/OS OPERATING SYSTEM EXPERIENCE

- Responsible for z/OS System Programming related to upgrading and maintaining of /OS Mini Systems and installation of products for testing. This includes the development of z/OS Systems operable at any given z/OS level for testing
- Creation of SMP/E and installation of z/OS Product Deliverables
- Creation, testing and publishing of SMP/E PTFs